ADITYA SAPKOTA

Auburn, AL | (+1)-334-559-1943 | adibit@outlook.com | LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With over 4 years of experience in Cloud ecosystem, IT infrastructure management and security baselines. Led diverse teams and digital transformations for two big Chemical factories spanning over 80+ countries. Served as a Computer Science lecturer at two national colleges. Recipient of Nepalese government grant worth NPR 600k for research of accessible EdTech projects. Microsoft Certified Trainer and Educator.

Research Interest: Cyber Security, Network & Infrastructure Security, Cloud Computing, AI in Security, Privacy and Governance

EDUCATION

Tribhuvan University

Kathmandu, Nepal

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology

2020

Coursework: Computer Networks, Cloud Computing, Operating System, Network and System Administration, Database Systems, Discrete Structure, Data Structure and Algorithms, Intro to Artificial Intelligence, Advanced Java.

• Designed Final Year Research Project titled "Barnamala: A Language Learning Tool" as a partial requirement for the degree of B.Sc. in Computer Science and Information Technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rapid Circle

Microsoft Cloud Engineer / Tech Operations Lead

Remote February 2021 – Present

(Rapid Circle is a multinational technology firm specializing in Microsoft cloud solutions, dedicated to helping organizations achieve digital transformation and enhanced efficiency.)

- Led a 17-person team to offer managed services for two international chemical factories, servicing over 24,000 users across 80+ countries and administered their Microsoft Cloud, and on-prem infrastructures.
- Implemented Cloud Security Standards for 5+ healthcare clients and deployed Microsoft Defender products, leading up to a 30% increase in their Microsoft Compliance & Secure Score.
- Collaborated with the Security Operations team to identify & assess and remediate vulnerabilities in infrastructures on VMware, Hyper-V, Intune, and Azure platforms.
- Maintained technical design & documentation of environments, processes, and procedures.

Universal College

Kathmandu, Nepal

Digital Strategist & Office 365 Consultant

November 2019 - January 2021

- Deployed and administered Office 365 for over 750 students and 65 staff across the primary and partner institutions, while also maintaining and securing the Windows server environment.
- Facilitated end-user training on Microsoft Teams and O365 apps for college-wide adoption, ensuring 95% of classes continued online without interruption during the COVID-19 pandemic.

HammerLab Creations

Kathmandu, Nepal

Co-Founder/Product Manager

2015 - 2020

(HammerLab Creation was a college venture, a creative studio specializing in apps and games.)

 Directed HammerLab Creations, steering a five-member team in mobile game development with design thinking and project management protocols, managing resources and budget, and setting KPI-linked milestones for goal tracking.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

New Summit College

Lecturer, Computer Science

Kathmandu, Nepal

January 2022 - October 2022

- Instructed three core courses—Cloud Computing, Computer Networking, and Operating Systems—to over 250 undergraduates in Computer Science, achieving a 95% pass rate.
- Facilitated Hands-on Lab training sessions on public cloud providers and virtualization platforms.
- Coordinated with computer science faculty to prepare and improve lab instructions and assignments.
- Coached an Azure Fundamentals Bootcamp, certifying over 50 students, offering mentorship for their entry into the cloud industry and guiding final-year students on major projects.

Thames International College

Kathmandu, Nepal

Lecturer, Computer Science

April 2022 - September 2022

- Taught Computer Networking course to 50 Undergraduate Computer Application students.
- Led hands-on computer network training sessions using tools such as Hyper-V, Wireshark, and Packet Tracer, enhancing real-world troubleshooting abilities.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Society of Information Technology Student (SITS), President

2017-2019

• Served a two-year tenure playing a significant role in conducting skill development workshops, technical boot camps, and hackathons for fellow students.

Kathmandu Youth Conclave (KYC), Lead Organizer

2018-2020

• Headed two editions of KYC, a national-level youth conference with a total of 7000+ participants. Link

TechTrix, Lead Organizer

2018-2020

• Directed two seasons of TechTrix, an intercollege Techfest with a national-level hackathon. Link

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Infrastructure: UNIX, Linux, Windows Server, Microsoft Azure, M365 Services, Virtualization, Docker, Kubernetes, Vulnerability Management, IT Operations.

Networking & Security: Network Administration & Automation, IAM, Cyber Security.

Programming: Python, C++, PowerShell, Bash, Terraform, SQL, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, pandas.

Soft Skills: Communication, Technical Documentation, Qualitative and quantitative research, Problem-Solving and Critical Thinking, Presentation, Teaching and Training Delivery, Upskilling, Adaptability

CERTIFICATIONS

•	Microsoft Certified Trainer (MCT) – Certificate	2020
•	Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104) – Certificate	2022
•	Microsoft 365 Certified: Administrator Expert (MS-102) – Certificate	2023
•	Coursera - Cybersecurity Specialization – University of Maryland	2023
•	Coursera - Cybersecurity in the Cloud Specialization - University of Minnesota	2020
•	Google - System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services – Certificate	2020

HONORS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded a Research Grant by the National Youth Council (Government of Nepal) to research accessible education technology for children with hearing impairment.
- Received Funds from Nepal Telecommunications Authority (Gov. Agency) for development and pilot deployment of Project **BhasaBuddy:** Gamified Language Learning tool in a <u>school for deaf children</u>.
- Secured second position in Hackathon on Accessible and Inclusive ICTs for Persons with Disabilities organized by LIRNEasia and Ford Foundation - Report

•	Selected as a Microsoft Student Partner (MSP) in 2017-2019 for being a mentor and leader in the college community on Microsoft technology to fellow students.